我们希望机器人的位置和方向随时间平滑变化
We want the position and orientation of our robot to vary smoothly with time as it’s
遵循轨迹。
following the trajectory.
出于多种原因，我们希望这样做。
We want to do this for a number of reasons.
首先，我们希望减少机器人的最大加速度。
Firstly, we want to reduce the maximum acceleration on the robot.
如果我们可以减少机器人的峰值加速度，那么我们可以减小尺寸
If we can reduce the peak acceleration of the robot, then we can reduce the size of
所需的电机。
the motors that are required.
如果轨迹是平滑的，那么它不会引起振动进入结构
If the trajectory is smooth, then it’s not going to induce vibrations into the structure
机器人
of the robot.
并且，对于非常非常大的机器人来说，这是一个重要的问题。但这提出了一个问题
And, this is an important issue with very, very large robots. But this raises the question
什么是光滑的？
of what is smooth?
现在，首先，我们希望机器人X的位置作为时间的函数是连续的，
Now, firstly, we want the position of the robot X as a function of time to be continuous,
没有不连续性。
to have no discontinuities.
我们还希望速度是连续的，加速度是连续的。
We also want the velocity to be continuous and the acceleration to be continuous.
也许，我们希望三阶导数（称为混蛋）是连续的
And perhaps, we want the third derivative, which is referred to as jerk, to be continuous
以及也许是第四衍生物等等。
as well and perhaps the fourth derivative and so on.
我们有很多平滑的数学函数，正弦曲线，高斯函数和多项式
There are very many smooth mathematical functions, sinusoids, Gaussians and polynomials that we
也许可以投入服务。
could perhaps press in to service.
在机器人技术中，最常用的是多项式。
In robotics, it’s most common to use polynomials.
并且，五次多项式，即五阶多项式，特别有用。
And, the quintic polynomial, that’s a fifth order polynomial, is particularly useful.
五次多项式有六个系数，A，B，C，D，E和F.
The quintic polynomial has got six coefficients, A, B, C, D, E and F.
我们将把案例S视为T的函数。所以，S就是这个位置
We’re going to consider the case S as a function of T. So, S is the position that
我们对在时间0开始并在时间T结束的轨迹感兴趣。优点
we’re interested in over a trajectory which starts at time 0 and ends at time T. The advantage
五次多项式的有六个系数，这意味着它有六个边界条件。
of the quintic polynomial is it got six coefficients and that means that it got six boundary conditions.
这意味着我们可以独立设置位置，速度和加速度
It means that we can independently set the position, the velocity and the acceleration
在开始时和结束时。
at the start time and at the end time.
这里的表格显示了我们用来表示这些边界的符号的名称
This table here then shows the names of the symbols that we used to denote these boundary
条件，初始和最终位置，初始和最终加速，初始和最终
conditions, initial and final position, initial and final acceleration, initial and final
加速。
acceleration.
这是我们的五次多项式，我可以计算它的导数
Here is our quintic polynomial again and I can compute its derivative with respect to
时间。
time.
因此，这是沿路径的速度，并且获得沿路径的加速度
So, this is the velocity along the path and the acceleration along the path is obtained
另一种衍生物。
by yet another derivative.
我可以在边界条件下替代。
I can substitute in the boundary conditions.
当时间等于0时，我在这里有这些关系。
When time equals 0, I have these relationships here.
而且，当时间等于T时，我在这里有这些关系。
And, when time equals T, I have these relationships
现在，我可以用矩阵形式写出这六个约束方程。
Now, I can write these six constraint equations in matrix form.
它看起来像这样。
It looks something like this.
矩阵是6乘6。
The matrix is 6 by 6.
它是正方形，这意味着我可以反转它。
It’s square, which means that I can invert it.
现在，我所拥有的是一种给出多项式系数A到的关系
And now, what I have is a relationship that gives me the polynomial coefficients A through
F就边界条件而言，矩阵基本上是一个函数
F in terms of the boundary conditions and a matrix which is essentially a function of
轨迹时间和一些常数。
the trajectory time and some constants.
让我们创建一个多项式轨迹，为此我将使用工具箱
Let’s create a polynomial trajectory and to do that I’m going to use the Toolbox
函数tpoly，轨迹多项式的简写。
function tpoly, short hand for trajectory polynomial.
多项式的初始值为0，最终值为1，有
The polynomial is going to have an initial value of 0, a final value of 1 and there are
将是50个步骤。
going to be 50 time steps.
在这里，我们可以看到轨迹。
And here, we can see the trajectory.
我们可以看到S从0开始并平稳上升并以1的值结算。
We can see that S starts off at 0 and rises smoothly and settles out at a value of 1.
我们可以看到速度从0开始并在0结束，加速也开始
We can see that the velocity starts at 0 and ends at 0 and the acceleration also starts
并以0的值结束。
and ends at the value of 0.
因此，改变最终条件。
And so, change the final condition.
因此，它不是从0变为1，而是从0变为-1，我们可以看到多项式
So, instead of going from 0 to 1, it goes from 0 to -1 and we can see the polynomial
现在正是如此。
now does exactly that.
如果我提供输出参数，我可以从这个函数中获取变量S的值
I can get the value of the variable S from this function if I provide an output argument
而不是生成一个图，它将返回矢量S.现在，我们在我们的工作区
and instead of producing a plot it will return the vector S. And now, we have in our workspace
S是具有50行和1列的向量，表示在50的每一个处的S的值
S which is a vector with 50 rows and one column, represents the value of S at each of the 50
时间步骤。
time steps.
我也可以要求速度和加速度，我将把它们放入变量中
I can also ask for the velocity and the acceleration and I’m going put those in to the variables
S点和S双点的SD和STD。
SD and STD for S dot and S double dot.
而且，我在我的工作空间中创建了一些额外的矢量变量
And again, I have created in my work space some additional vector variables, each of
他们有50行。
them has got 50 rows.
行对应于时间步长。
The rows correspond to the time steps.
您将在所有图中注意到初始速度和最终速度等于0。
You'll notice in all the plots that the initial and final velocities have been equal to 0.
好吧，我可以通过为初始值提供显式值来覆盖它，我将会这样做
Well, I can override that by providing explicit values for the initial and I’m going to
要求初始速度为0.5，我将要求最终速度
ask the initial velocity to be 0.5 and I’m going to ask for the final velocity
等于0。
to be equal to 0.
你可以看到的是，初始速度现在等于0.5，最终速度等于
What you can see is the initial velocity now is equal to 0.5, final velocity is equal to
0。
0.
但是，你会注意到的是，如果你看一下S的情节，你会发现它已经消失了
But, what you'll notice is if you look at the plot of S, you’ll see that it has gone
从0到1，但它已大量超调。
from 0 to 1, but it has massively overshot.
它已经上升到5，然后降低到所需的最终值。
It has gone up as high as 5 and then reduced to the desired final value.
通过改变边界条件，我们已经大大改变了轨迹的形状。
By changing the boundary conditions, we have dramatically changed the shape of the trajectory.
因此，我们已经看到五次多项式使得从0到0的平滑曲线变得漂亮
So, we have seen that the quintic polynomial makes nice, smooth curves moving from 0 to
在50个时间单位的时间内，我们可以看到速度是平滑的和加速度
1 over a period of 50 time units and we can see that the velocity is smooth and the acceleration
很顺利
is smooth.
但是，这里有一点问题。
But, there’s a bit of a problem here.
那就是机器人进行的峰值速度值为0.038单位，
That is that the peak velocity that the robot undertakes has got a value of 0.038 units,
但是路径上的平均速度要小得多。
but the average velocity over the path is much, much less.
这只是.02。
It’s only .02.
平均而言，我们只能达到此路径峰值速度的52％。
On average, we’re only going at 52% of the peak velocity for this path.
因此，这意味着对于大多数路径而言，电机不能尽可能地工作
So, that means that for most of the path, the motor isn't working as hard as it could
是。
be.
这意味着我们必须安装一台可以达到这个峰值速度的电机，但主要是我们
It means that we have to install a motor which can go at this peak speed but mostly we’re
没有使用那个容量。
not using that capacity.
我们在浪费表现。
We’re wasting performance.
这也意味着我们需要更长时间才能到达我们想去的地方。
It also means that it’s going to take us longer to get where we want to go.